Guide to the Brigid Maire Clark Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Brigid Maire Clark papers
1983-1992
MS 1633
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The papers consist of writings, notes, and biographical material of Brigid Maire Clark.
Clark, Brigid Maire, 1965-1992
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dennis Clark, 1992.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Brigid Maire Clark was born on March 17, 1965, in Pennsylvania. She graduated from Abington Friends School in Jenkintown, Pennsylvania, in 1983; received her B.A. from Yale University in 1987, where she majored in English; and her M.A. in writing from Vermont College in 1990. At Yale, Brigid Clark received the Wallace Fiction Prize, the James A. Veech Prize for outstanding undergraduate imaginative writing, and the Robert C. Bates Traveling Fellowship, which she used to interview writers in Ireland. Brigid Clark died on January 28, 1992, in Montpelier, Vermont. At the time of her death, Clark was coordinator of off-campus studies and a contributing faculty member at Goddard College. She had also been accepted to the MacDowell Colony.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of writings, notes, and biographical material of Brigid Maire Clark.
Fiction -- Women authors; Short stories -- Women authors; Women authors; Authors; Clark, Brigid Maire, 1965-1992
- Inventory
  - Writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Writings: drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
  - "From Seneca," Part 1 of Last Pale Witch, an unfinished novella, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Commentaries by Brigid Maire Clark on readings, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Daily themes, Yale University, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lecture notes, Goddard College, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - MacDowell Colony: application, 1991 August (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Biographical material, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memorials, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)